walgreens.com 2018-12-26

# Online Privacy and Security Policy | Walgreens

## Help Center

  * Account
  * Balance Rewards
  * Balance Rewards for healthy choices®")
  * Shopping Online
  * Auto-Reorder & Save
  * Pre-Order
  * Promotions
  * Coupons
  * Checkout
  * Payment Methods
  * Gift Cards
  * Shipping
  * Ship to Store 
  * Returns
  * Pharmacy
  * Pharmacy Resources
  * Walgreens Health Services
  * Customer Service
  * Walgreens Stores
  * Company Info
  * Mobile and Social Media
  * Same Day Services (Gainesville, FL)")

This Privacy Policy lets you know how we collect, use, share, and protect information about you. By interacting with Walgreens through our stores, websites, mobile applications, and any other Walgreens affiliate sites where you may interact with Walgreens, you consent to the practices described in this privacy notice. Any changes in our Privacy Policy will appear on this page so that you are aware of the data we collect and how we use it.

In some circumstances, Walgreens use of your information will be subject to the requirements of the Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (commonly known as "HIPAA"). For example, if you log into your pharmacy account and submit information regarding a prescription order, that information is subject to HIPAA requirements. In those circumstances, Walgreens Notice of Privacy Practices and not this Privacy Policy will apply. If you have questions about which policy applies to the information you have submitted, please do not hesitate to [Contact Us](mailto:privacy.office@walgreens.com).

##### **Our Privacy Guarantee**

At Walgreens, we are committed to maintaining our customers' privacy. We take great care to safeguard the personal information that we collect to ensure that our customers' privacy is maintained. We have provided this notice to you to describe information collection and use practices at Walgreens. This notice describes the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

Your personally identifiable information is information that can be used to identify or contact you. Your name, home address, telephone number, and email address are examples of personally identifiable information. Personal information does not include aggregated or de-identified information.

##### **Information We Collect:**

We want you to understand how information you provide to us is collected and used. When you interact with Walgreens or use our services, we collect certain information about you and the services you use. An example of using our "services" would be when you visit one of our stores or websites. We may collect and store information from you in the following situations:

**Information you provide to us directly when you:**

  * Make an in-store or online purchase, or other transaction with us;
  * Create an account on one of our websites or mobile application;
  * Participate in our loyalty programs, such as Balance Rewards or Balance Rewards for healthy choices®;
  * Participate in a contest, sweepstake, promotion, or survey;
  * Request customer service including dispute resolution, correspondence through our sites, and correspondence sent to us; or
  * Post a review or comment on one of our website, or post other user-generated content on one of our websites or mobile services

**Information you provide through the use of our services, including:**

**Device Information**

  * We may collect device-specific information when you visit our websites or use our mobile applications or services. This includes information such as Internet Protocol (IP) address, hardware model, operating system, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information. We may also associate the information we collect from your different devices, which helps us provide consistent services across your devices.

**Log Information**

  * This includes details of how you used our sites or mobile applications including clicks and page information such as the address (or URL) of the website or mobile application you came from before visiting our site or mobile application, which pages you visit on our site or application, which browser you used to view our site or mobile application, and any search terms entered.
  * Other information from your interaction with our sites, services, content and advertising, including computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, ad data and other standard weblog information.

**Location Information**

  * When you use our services, we may collect information about your physical location through the use of our Services on your mobile phone or device by, for example using satellite, cell phone tower, WiFi signal, beacons, Bluetooth and near field communication protocols, when you are in or near a Walgreens store. For example, through mobile services, Bluetooth & WiFi technology in our stores may allow us to recognize the location of a mobile device in our stores when you opt-in to allowing us to collect this information.

**In-Store Cameras**

  * We use in-store cameras for security purposes and for operational purposes such as measuring traffic patterns and tracking in-stock levels.

**Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies:**

  * "Cookies" are small data files that are sent from a website's server and are stored on your device's hard drive either for only the duration of your visit ("session cookies") or for a fixed period of time ("persistent cookies"). Cookies may store user preferences and other types of information. We use cookies to provide features and services, such as:

  * Remembering your preferences and allowing you to enter your user name less frequently;
  * Presenting information that's targeted to your interests, including Walgreens content presented on another website;
  * Measuring the effectiveness of our sites, services, content and advertising
  * Providing other services and features that are available only through the use of cookies.
  * The Options/Settings section of most internet browsers will tell you how to manage cookies and other technologies that may be transferred to your device, including how to disable these technologies. You can disable our cookies or all cookies through your browser setting, but please note that disabling cookies may impact some of our website's features and prevent the site from operating properly.

  * A "Web Beacon" is an electronic image placed in the code of a webpage, application, or email. We use web beacons to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page to another and to improve site performance.

**Flash Cookies:**

  * We may use or engage a third party that uses Local Stored Objects, sometimes referred to as "Flash Cookies," and other technologies to collect and store information about the use of our services. A Flash cookie is a small data file placed on your computer or device using Adobe Flash technology. Flash cookies are different from the cookies discussed above because cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To limit the websites that can store information in Flash cookies on your device, you must visit the Adobe website: **<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>**

**Information We Collect From Other Sources:**

  * We may collect information that is publicly available. For example, we may collect information you submit to a blog, chat room, or social network. We also may collect information from other companies, organizations, or third-party partners. For example, we may receive information about you from a partner when we jointly offer services or from an advertiser about your experiences with them. By gathering additional information about you, we can correct inaccurate information and give you product recommendations and special offers more likely to interest you.

##### **How We Use Your Information:**

Our primary purpose in collecting information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. We may use your information in a variety of ways, including for the following purposes:

**Product and Service Fulfillment**

  * We use your contact information to respond to your inquiries, fulfill your requests and improve your experience.

**Our Marketing Purposes**

  * We use your information to deliver coupons, mobile coupons, newsletters, e-mails, mobile messages, and social media notifications about our brands, products, events or other promotional purposes.

**Internal Operations**

  * We use your information to improve the effectiveness of our services, conduct research and analysis, or to perform other business activities as needed.

**Prevention of Fraud and other Harm**

  * We use your information to detect, prevent or investigate potential security breaches, fraudulent transactions and monitor against theft.

**Legal Compliance**

  * We may use your information to assist law enforcement and respond to regulatory or other legal inquiries.

##### **How We Share Your Information:**

We do not sell, rent, or loan your personal information to any non-affiliated third parties, except as described in this Policy. We will only share your information with companies, organizations and individuals outside of Walgreens as described below:

**When We Work With Service Providers**

  * We may share your information with affiliated and unaffiliated companies that perform tasks on our behalf related to our business. Such tasks include analyzing site usage data, customer service, electronic and postal mail service, and social and other media services. Third-party service providers only receive your information as necessary to perform their role, and we instruct them not to use your Information for any other purposes.
  * We may work with other companies who place cookies, tags, and web beacons on our websites. These companies help operate our websites and provide you with additional products and services.
  * We may also use third party advertising networks to serve advertisements on our behalf. The cookies received with the banner advertisements served by these networks may be used to collect and build behavioral profiles by these companies to deliver targeted advertisements on our website and unaffiliated websites.

**When We Work With Third Party Partners**

  * We may work with other companies who operate their own websites or mobile applications, to allow them to offer Walgreens customers the ability to connect to Walgreens services. These services give you more options for ways to use Walgreens services from websites or apps that are not owned or operated by Walgreens.
  * We contract with companies to allow Walgreens customers to access their Balance Rewards account from those partners' websites and/or mobile apps. This may include the ability to join Balance Rewards, add an existing Balance Rewards membership, and/or access your account balance.
  * Balance Rewards for healthy choices® members may choose to connect their accounts with third party apps and devices in order to earn points for their healthy activities. Notwithstanding the uses and disclosures set forth above, Walgreens will not use or disclose to third parties user data gathered under the Balance Rewards for healthy choices® program for advertising or other use-based data mining purposes other than improving health, or for the purpose of health research. In no event will any information be collected from Balance Rewards for healthy choices® members for use by third parties in compliance with this section without obtaining user consent.

**When Sharing is Required by Law or Helps Us Protect Our Interests**

  * We will use and disclose your information as necessary or appropriate under applicable law, to comply with legal process, to respond to such requests from public and government authorities, to enforce our terms and conditions, including investigations of potential violations, to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and to allow us to pursue available remedies to limit the damages that we may sustain. In matters involving claims of personal or public safety or in litigation where the data is pertinent, we may use or disclose personal information without your consent or court process.

**When We Work On Business Transactions**

  * As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores or assets, or as part of a merger, acquisition, sale of company assets, in connection with the evaluation of and entry into such transactions, or in the course of providing transition of services to another provider. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Additionally, in the unlikely event that Walgreens or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets and is permissible under law.

**Non-identifiable or Aggregate information with Third Parties**

  * We may share non-identifiable or aggregate information with third parties for lawful purposes.

**With Your Consent**

  * At your direction or request, or when you otherwise consent, we may share your information.

##### **Your Choices:**

By interacting with any of the Walgreens Family of Companies as described above, you consent to the practices described in this privacy notice. However, we want you to know that you do have certain choices with regard to how your information is collected and used.

**Email and Mobile Communications**

  * You may choose to stop receiving e-mail and mobile marketing communications by changing your preferences online. If you have an online account, login to Your Account and click on Communication Preferences. If you do not have an online account you may click Unsubscribe from the bottom of Walgreens emails, and reply STOP to our text messages to stop receiving emails and SMS text messages. To request unsubscribing by email, contact [Customerservice@mail2.walgreens.com](mailto:Customerservice@mail2.walgreens.com).

**Mobile Application**

  * **Push Notifications**  
You can opt out from further allowing Walgreens to send you push notifications by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device or from the Walgreens app.
  * **Geo-Location**  
You can opt out from further allowing Walgreens to access location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device.
  * **In-Store Location**  
You can opt out from further allowing Walgreens to access your in-store location by adjusting the location permissions in your mobile device or from the Walgreens app.

**Online Tracking and Interest-Based Advertisements**

  * Walgreens engages third party advertisers to provide interest-based advertising on our website, as well as other third party sites in order to display advertising that is relevant to you. These third parties may collect information about your use of our services over time and that information may be combined with information collected on different websites and online services.  
These third party advertisers may be participants in the Network Advertising Initiative and/or the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising, which allow users to opt out of ad targeting from participating companies. To learn more about interest-based advertising, or to opt-out of having your web browsing information used by certain third party advertisers for behavioral advertising purposes, go to [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.

**_Please Note:_** When you "opt-out" of receiving interest-based advertisements, this does not mean you will no longer see advertisements from Walgreens. It means that the online ads that you do see will not be tailored for you based on your particular interests. We may still collect information about you for any purpose permitted under the Policy, including for analytics and fraud prevention.

**Our "Do Not Track" Policy**

  * Walgreens respects enhanced user privacy controls. We support the development and implementation of a standard "do not track" browser feature, which signals to websites that you visit that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. Please note that at this time Walgreens.com does not interpret or respond to "do not track" signals. However, you may set your Web browser to not accept new cookies or web beacons, be notified when you receive a new cookie, or disable cookies altogether. Please note that by disabling these features, your experience on Walgreens.com will not be as smooth and you will not be able to take full advantage of our website's features. Please see the Help section of your browser for instructions on managing security preferences.

**Minors**

  * If you are under 18 years old and a registered user, you can request that we remove content or information that you have posted to our website or other online services. Note that fulfilment of the request may not ensure complete or comprehensive removal (e.g., if the content or information has been reposted by another user). To request removal of content or information, please [contact us](mailto:privacy.office@walgreens.com).

**Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information**

  * You can review and update any of the information you have given us by emailing us or calling (877) 924-4472. Our customer care staff will update your information. If you have a Walgreens.com account, you can log in and update your information.

##### **Links to Third-Party Sites:**

Our Services may contain links to, or otherwise make available, social media sites and other third party services, websites and mobile applications that are operated and controlled by third parties. We do not take responsibility for the content or the privacy practices employed by other sites. Unless otherwise stated, any Information you provide to any such third party site will be collected by that party and not by Walgreens, and will be subject to that party's privacy policy (if any), rather than this Privacy Notice. In such a situation, we will have no control over, and shall not be responsible for, that party's use of the Information you provide to them.

##### **Location-Based Services:**

When you download our mobile application, you can opt-in to location sharing for additional application capabilities. If you have opted-in to sharing your location information, we may use various technologies to collect your information as described in this policy to provide you with location-based services and content, including for marketing purposes. For example, using the Store Locator feature in our mobile application can allow you to quickly find the nearest Walgreens location. To learn how to opt-out of sharing your location information with Walgreens, go to the "Your Choices" section of this Privacy Policy.

##### **How We Protect Your Information:**

**Security Measures**

  * Walgreens recognizes the importance of maintaining the security of your personal information. Whether you are shopping on our website, through our mobile services, or in our stores, we use reasonable security measures, including administrative, technical, and physical safeguards.

**Email Security**

  * "Phishing" is a common email scam where your email address is used to contact you and ask for personal or sensitive information. Always be cautious when opening links or attachments from unsolicited third parties. Also know that Walgreens will not send you emails asking for your credit card number, social security number or other personally identifiable information. If you are ever asked for this information, you can be confident it is not from Walgreens.

**Children's Personal Information**

  * We recognize the importance of protecting children's online privacy. Our website and mobile services are intended for a general audience and are not directed to children. We do not knowingly collect personal information online from children under the age of 13.

**How To Contact Us:**  
If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, contact us by:  
Phone: (877) 924-4472  
E-mail: [privacy.office@walgreens.com](mailto:privacy.office@walgreens.com)  
Regular mail:  
Walgreen Co. Privacy Office  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
200 Wilmot Rd, MS 9000  
Deerfield, IL 60015  

**Effective Date:** 10/21/2016

Beginning of dialog content for session timeout overlay Close  ‹ Back  **Are You Still There?**

Due to inactivity, you will be signed out of Walgreens.com soon.  
Please choose to continue your session or sign out now.

**Pick up where you left off?**

You've been signed out due to inactivity, but it's easy to pick up where you left off on Walgreens.com.

Return to MyPrime.com

Due to inactivity, you'll need to go back and   
start the process from the beginning.

End of dialog content for session timeout overlay
